여보세요
It's me. I know you
can 't stand to see me.
나야, 네 꼴 보기 싫으면
전화로 사과할 테니까...
I'm trying to apologize
over the phone
넵?
I shouldn't have kissed
your girlfriend
네 여자와 키스를 하다니...
Stop calling!
전화질 그만해!
This is 92.3 WXRK, K-Rock...
안녕하십니까, 92. 3 WXRK
케이락 방송국입니다
...calling with our $ 1000
daily challenge!
- 천 달러의 행운을 잡으세요
- 거 좋죠
All right!
What is the name of...
현재 죄책감에 시달리고 있는
선생님의 룸메이트는 누구...
...your roommate who is very sorry
and would do anything?
-Damn it, Chandler, stop calling.
-Joey, it's Ross.
- 챈들러, 그만 해둬!
- 나야, 로스
미안하다
-Sorry.
-It's all right.
- 괜찮아
- 무슨 일로?
What's up?
Not much. I got Chandler
here and he's really, really sorry
별일은 아니고
여기 있는 챈들러가
진심으로...
The One with Chandler in a Box
Oh, turkey!
어! 칠면조
윽! 추수야, 감사하다
Giving thanks!
Look, everyone.
It's the spirit of Thanksgiving!
잘 들어, 이게 바로
추수감사절 정신이야
Are things with Joey better?
- 조이와는 어떻게 됐어?
- 갈수록 태산이야
They couldn't be worse.
I spent eight hours calling him...
간밤에 여덟 시간이나 전화통
붙들고 사정해도 소용없어
...trying to get him
to talk to me.
여덟 시간이나?
Eight hours.
You could probably use
a plug-in telephone headset.
헤드셋을 쓰는 게
낫지 않았을까?
Should we all expect Christmas gifts
that are stolen from your office?
사무실에서 훔친 물건으로
우리 성탄절 선물 돌리게?
You shouldn't.
넌 포기해라
성탄절 말인데
Speaking of Christmas....
모니카랑 동업하느라
내 돈은 바닥이 났거든?
Since Monica and I are starting
a new business and have no money...
금년엔 각자 비밀 산타가 돼서
선물을 하나씩만 준비하자고
...this year we could do Secret Santa
and each only buy one gift.
신나는 미스터리도 있잖아?
누가 누가 걸리나
And there's the added mystery
of who gets who.
Who gets whom.
누구 누구 걸려라
I don't know why I do that.
내가 요즘 왜 이러지?
But it is correct.
그래도 말은 바로 해야지
Hey, what's this?
It's all of your names.
이게 뭐지?
우리 이름이다, 뽑자
Let's pick.
Hey, what's going?
뭣들 해?
-No, Joey, stay.
-We're picking names for Secret Santa.
- 가지 마, 조이
- 우리 비밀 산타 뽑는 중이야
Okay.
그래
I invented Secret Santa, you know.
그건 내가 개발했는데
What are you laughing at? You're the
one who said Die Hard was your idea.
뭘 웃어? '다이 하드'는
네 아이디어라면서?
It was.
물론이지
Don't make me show you the napkin.
아이디어 적어둔
냅킨 보여줄까?
I'm going to take a nap.
Turkey makes me sleepy.
낮잠이나 자련다
칠면조 때문에 졸려
We haven't eaten yet.
먹지도 않았잖아
I know, but all that work
you're doing to get it ready and....
입맛 다시고 있기도
너무 따분하다 얘
Did you pick Rachel for your
Secret Santa? I'll trade for her.
혹시 너희 둘 중에 레이첼의
비밀 산타 있음 나랑 바꾸자
I picked her.
Thank God, you want her!
나한테 걸렸어
살았다! 가져가
Why do you want to get
rid of her so badly?
왜 그렇게 좋아해?
선물 받으면 늘 다시 바꿔
애가 워낙 까다로워야지
She exchanges every gift she gets.
It's impossible to get her
something she likes.
Come on, let's trade!
빨랑 바꿔!
I got her that backpack
and she loved it.
무슨 소리야, 내가 사준
배낭을 얼마나 좋아했는데
I remember she cried
when that big dog ran off with
그걸 개가 물고 가서
눈물을 펑펑...
There was no big dog.
개 같은 건 없었구만
This sucks! I already got her
a briefcase with "R.G." put on it.
서류가방을 하나 사서
'RG'까지 새겼는데 일 났네
Her initials.
레이첼 이니셜
Okay, I'm really bad at initials.
내가 이니셜에 좀 약해
You got your shopping done early.
- 올해는 선물을 빨리 샀네?
- 카드가 만료되기 직전이라
Yeah, well, my Camel Cash
was about to expire.
Maybe you can give it to somebody
else. Like Ross Geller!
다른 사람 주면 어때
로스 겔러도 있네
You know what?
It's a girlie briefcase.
여성용으로 나온 거라...
Who cares!
He works in a museum.
박물관에서 일하는데
무슨 상관이야
The big game's about to start!
이런!
게임 시작할 시간인데
Ross and Joey aren't here.
You can watch the parade if you want.
됐어, 로스랑 조이 없으니까
퍼레이드나 봐
Thanks.
고마워
냉장고가 왜 이래?
What is wrong with this freezer?
-What happened?
-lce just got in my eye!
- 왜 그래?
- 눈에 얼음이 들어갔어
People are trying
to sleep in here!
나 취침 좀 할까?
Monica got ice in her eye
and it hurts!
모니카 눈에 얼음이 들어갔대
-Open it up. Let me see.
-I can't. It really kills.
- 눈 좀 떠봐, 어디 보자
- 안 떠져, 너무 아파
얼음찜질을 해봐
Maybe you should put
some ice on it.
-lt looks bad.
-We should take you to a doctor.
- 너무 심한데?
- 병원에 가자
No, my eye doctor is Richard!
내 안과주치의는 리처드야
애인도 없이 거길 가나?
I can't go to him
when I don't have a boyfriend.
He's really picky about his patients.
환자 한번 까다롭게 고르네
You've got to go.
What's his office number?
그래도 가봐야지
전화번호 불러봐
Like I remember his office number!
내가 그걸 외우고 다니나?
Speed dial seven.
단축다이얼 7
I'm calling on behalf
of Monica Geller's eye.
모니카 겔러의 눈을
대신해서 전화 드렸는데
Is Richard Burke in today?
리처드 버크 박사님 계세요?
He's not in. Will she
see the on-call doctor?
출장중이래
당직 의사도 괜찮겠니?
-Yes.
-She's very excited about that!
- 그럼!
- 네!무지 좋아하네요
Okay, we'll be right in.
곧 갈게요
Okay, so who's gonna take her in?
누가 같이 갈래?
I'll go, you can watch your parade.
내가 갈게
넌 퍼레이드나 봐
It's so cool.
Till Monica gets back, I'm head chef.
너무 좋다, 모니카 없으면
내가 주방장이지 뭐
And I get to make all the decisions.
전부 내 맘이야
She told you to follow
the recipe exactly.
조리법대로 하랬잖아
Get out of my kitchen.
내 주방에서 나가
I think I'm making
some progress with Joey.
좋았어, 약간 진전이
보이는 것 같아
When I walked in,
he went to his bedroom...
날 보자마자 침실 문을 꽝 닫고
들어갔는데 딱 한 번으로 끝났어
...but he only slammed the door once.
Yeah, he gave me the finger
while doing it.
그 와중에 손가락을
치켜세우긴 하더라
I've got to call my mom and
ask her a left-handed cooking question.
엄마한테 왼손잡이 조리법에
대해 물어봐야겠다
I'm gonna be in there.
잠깐 갔다 올게
나 없는 동안...
While I'm gone....
Chandler, you're in charge.
챈들러, 네가 대장해
I picked Monica for Secret Santa, but
I'm getting her something for Hanukkah.
난 모니카의 산타인데
하누카 명절에도 선물을
줘야 돼, 나랑 바꿀래?
You want to switch?
I was trying to trade...
내가 선물 주려고
생각한 사람은 넌데
...for you.
Really? That's so nice.
What are you getting me?
진짜? 그랬구나
뭘 준비했는데?
글쎄, 여성스런 감각의
소지품이 어떨까 해
I don't know, R.G. I was thinking
something girlie for your office.
그럼 피비랑 바꿔야겠다
Maybe Phoebe will switch with me.
포기해, 그쪽은 선물만 받으면
교환하러 다니는 레이첼이거든
Then you'll get stuck with Rachel,
and she exchanges every gift.
무슨 소리, 내 선물은
안 바꾸고 잘만 쓰더라
No, I got her lots of stuff
she never took back.
가령?
Like?
Like that gold necklace
I got her last year.
작년에 사준 금목걸이
마지막으로 찬 게 언제지?
When did she wear it last?
She wore it all Christmas day
and then....
성탄절에 하루 종일
걸고 있다가...
Big dog?
개가 나타났지?
- 조이
- 어서 와
What are you doing?
뭐해?
챈들러 녀석이 뇌물로
사들인 물건을 반품하려고
Sending back this stuff
Chandler bought.
-Even the TV?
-No, I'll put that in my room.
- TV까지 몽땅?
- 아니, 그건 내 방에 둘 거야
Listen, Joey.
I know what he did was wrong.
이봐, 조이
잘못한 건 사실이지만
말도 못 붙이게 하면 어떡해
But can't you hear him out?
If Chandler had kissed Rachel,
would you hear him out?
옛날에 그 녀석이 레이첼이랑
키스했다면 넌 쉽게 봐주겠냐?
That's a good point.
예리하군
How long you going to punish him?
- 얼마나 고통을 줄 건데?
- 5년
Five years.
You've sentenced him?
형까지 선고했냐?
처벌이 겁나면
죄를 짓지 말아야지
Don't do the crime
if you can't do the time.
The guy's your best friend.
- 둘도 없는 친구잖아
- 둘도 없는 친구였지
Was my best friend.
I don't know why
you're pushing for him.
왜 그렇게 감싸고돌아?
With him out of the way as
my best friend, there's a spot open.
녀석이 밀려나면
그 자리는 공석인데?
-Who, me?
-Yeah.
- 누구, 나?
- 그럼
그거 영광이다
I'm honored. You know what
I'm going to do as your best friend?
둘도 없는 친구로서 충고하지
챈들러랑 얘기해 봐
I'm going to get you
to talk to Chandler.
All right.
알았어, 둘도 없는
친구의 부탁이니까
But if you weren't
my best friend....
Oh, my God. Is it really that bad?
상황이 그렇게 험악해요?
I walk in the room,
and he won't talk to me.
방에 들어가면 말도 안 하고
무슨 이태리어를 중얼거려요
He just mumbles something in ltalian.
And I know he only knows
the bad words.
그 나라 말은
욕밖에 모를 텐데
미안해요
다 나 때문이에요
I'm so, so sorry.
I feel responsible.
It's not your fault.
당신 잘못 없어요
-Gunther, have you seen Chandler?
-I thought you were Chandler.
건터, 챈들러 봤어요?
댁이 챈들러 아냐?
But one of you is over there.
자네 분신은 저쪽에 있어
어머!
Hey, Joe.
너 왔니?
바 파 나뽈리!
I'll be right with you.
Thanks for coming in.
잠깐만 기다리세요
고마워요
Oh, my God!
How cute is the on-call doctor?
맙소사
어쩜 저렇게 귀엽지?
So cute that I'm thinking
about jamming this pen in my eye.
나도 펜으로 눈이나
한번 쑤셔볼까?
-You have the best luck with eye doctors.
-I know.
- 넌 의사 복 터졌다
- 그러게!
Dr. Burke will see you now.
버크 박사님께서
들어오시랍니다
버크 박사님이 아니라
당직 의사라고 들었는데요
Not Dr. Burke.
The on-call doctor will see me now.
Dr. Richard Burke is out.
리처드 버크 박사의 아드님
티모시 버크 박사님이세요
Dr. Timothy Burke, his son,
will see you now.
Ready?
준비됐나요?
Hey, I'm sorry. That
미안하다, 그건...
-Where you going?
-My folks'.
어디 가냐?
부모님 댁에
When you coming back?
언제 올 건데?
I don't know. I might stay there
while I look for an apartment.
글쎄, 거기 있으면서
새 집을 구해보련다
What?
뭐?
난 대화로 풀어질 줄 알았는데
두 사람이 같이 있는 걸 보니..
I thought we could talk
about this. Work it out.
Seeing you two together, I don't....
대체 원하는 게 뭐야?
캐시를 만나지 말라고?
What do you want me to say?
Should I stop seeing her?
It's not about her. Okay?
문제는 캐시가 아냐, 알아?
But seeing you together
reminds me of what you did.
그 꼴을 보니까
다시 부아가 치민다고
I won't live with someone who doesn't
know what it is to be a friend.
우정이 뭔지도 모르는 녀석과
살고 싶진 않아, 나 간다
I know what it is to be a friend.
I screwed up.
나도 우정이 뭔지는 알지만
맘처럼 되는 게 아니잖아
맞아, 그렇지
Yeah, you did.
And that's why I'm leaving.
그래서 나가는 거야
If you're not going to stay for me,
then at least stay for them.
정 내가 보기 싫다면
쟤들 보고 살아
도둑맞고 나서
얼마나 충격이 큰데
They had a very difficult year.
What with the robbery and all.
And that chick used to be very cute.
얼굴 상한 것 좀 봐
When that guy was robbing us...
도둑놈 때문에 장 속에
여섯 시간이나 갇혀서
...and I was locked in the
entertainment unit for six hours...
무슨 생각한 줄 알아?
너한테 미안한 맘뿐이었어
...do you know what I was doing?
I was thinking about
how I let you down.
그래!
If I knew what kind of friend
you'd be, I wouldn't have worried.
넌 원래 이런 놈이었는데
괜한 짓을 했지 싶다, 간다
잠깐 기다려 봐
방법을 한번 찾아보자
Wait one second! There has
to be something that I can do.
If we still had that unit...
그 장만 있으면 나도 들어가서
여섯 시간 동안 미안해할 거야
...I'd get in it for six hours
and think about how I let you down.
What?
뭐?
We got a box.
궤짝은 있네
I remember the last time I saw you.
대학기숙사로 떠나던 날 아침
당신을 마지막으로 봤어요
It was the morning I left for college.
You were standing
outside the Dairy Queen.
아이스크림가게 앞에서
Just probably waiting for it to open.
문 열기를 기다렸죠
-You look great now.
-You look great too.
- 아주 좋아 보이는데요?
- 그쪽도 좋아 보여요
You're an excellent patient.
만점짜리 환자군요
How does it look?
상태는 어때요?
You have a scratch on your cornea.
You have to wear a patch.
각막이 약간 긁혔군요
며칠 안대를 해야겠어요
Like a pirate?
해적처럼?
If that helps you.
그래야 낫죠
아버지하고는
언제부터 일했어요?
How long have you been working
with your dad?
Come on, one of us had to mention him.
피할 이유는 없잖아요
I moved back here a couple months ago.
온 지 두어 달 됐어요
Big family dinner tonight?
오늘은 가족 만찬이겠죠?
- 이거...
- 말도 안돼
No way!
I was gonna have Thanksgiving
at my girlfriend's.
추수감사절은 여자친구랑
보낼 생각이었는데...
But we broke up.
헤어졌어요
심각한 관계를
꺼리더라구요
She wasn't ready
for a serious commitment.
So you made her walk the plank,
aye, matey?
그래서 고기밥으로 줘버렸나?
You're not wearing the patch yet.
아직 안대를 안 했는데
I know.
알아요
-He's coming here for Thanksgiving?
-I know. It's sick.
- 여기서 추수감사절을 쇤다고?
- 좀 그렇다 얘
-Why is it sick?
-It's Richard's son!
그렇긴 뭐가 그래
리처드의 아들이잖아
'희랍 비극'이랑 저녁을 먹어?
It's like inviting
a Greek tragedy over for dinner.
If it were Greek,
I'd be blind in both eyes.
그게 희랍 비극이면
두 눈이 다 멀어도 좋아
I like him because he's handsome and
he's nice and smart and handsome.
너무 핸섬하고, 자상하고
똑똑하고... 핸섬하잖아
피비, 넌 이해하지?
Phoebe, you understand, don't you?
I could see where I'd be
your best shot, but no.
안타깝지만 이해 못해
Sorry, honey. I think it's twisted.
너무 꼬인 관계야
- 꼬이다니 뭐가?
- 나랑 리처드의 아들
-What's twisted?
-Me going out with Richard's son.
저런!
저런! 저런! 저런!
It sounds like a really bad idea to me.
내가 볼 때도
불량한 발상이야
-ls he okay in there?
-He's fine!
- 쟤 괜찮을까?
- 괜찮고말고!
If things work out
between you and Richard's son...
두 사람 잘되면 애들한테
할아버지하고 잤다고 할래?
...you can tell your kids...
...that you slept
with their grandfather.
Judge all you want to.
다들 잘 빠졌어
Married a lesbian,
left a man at the altar...
레즈비언이랑 결혼하고
식장에서 뛰쳐나오고
게이 아이스댄서한테 혹하고
불 속에 여자 의족 집어던지고
...Ioved a gay ice dancer...
...threw a girl's wooden leg
in the fire, live in a box!
궤짝에 갇힌 주제에!
What exactly is the point of the box?
- 이 궤짝의 포인트가 뭐지?
- 챈들러?
The meaning of the box is threefold.
궤짝의 의미는 삼겹이지
One, it gives me the time
to think about what I did.
하나, 내 과오를 뉘우치는 뜻
Two, it proves how much I care
about my friendship with Joey.
둘, 조이와의 우정을
증명하는 뜻
And three...
마지막으로 셋!
...it hurts.
삭신이 쑤신다!
And if he stays in the box
you guys will be friends again?
이 안에 있으면 너희 둘
다시 친구가 되는 거야?
Let's just say it's a start.
그게 시작이지
Remember that necklace
I gave you last year?
저기, 작년에 내가 준 목걸이
지금 좀 볼 수 있어?
Can I see it?
Why?
- 왜?
- 확인할 게 있어서
I just want to check something.
Okay.
좋아
Now we'll see.
- 어디 한번 볼까?
- 숨구멍! 숨구멍!
Air hole! Air hole!
Here it is. I love it.
I wear it all the time.
여기, 맘에 쏙 들어서
늘 차고 다녔어
The necklace I got you was gold.
This is silver.
내가 준 건 금인데
이건 은이잖아
Well, maybe...
이게 혹시...
변신을 했나?
...it changed.
Oh, my God!
You actually exchanged it.
못살아, 가서 바꿨구만
Isn't it better to exchange it
for something I enjoy...
마냥 묵혀두느니 바꾸면
떨어지는 것도 많고 좀 좋아?
...and can use a lot?
What did you get?
뭐가 떨어지는데?
Credit.
상품권
내가 갈게, 내가 갈게...
I'll get it. I'll get it. I'll get it.
I'll get it. I'll get it.
어서 와요
Hi, Tim.
고마워요
Thank you.
Come meet my friends.
친구들이랑 인사해요
- 이쪽은... 피비
- 반갑습니다
Phoebe.
And Joey.
조이
My brother, Ross.
우리 오빠 로스
And Rachel.
레이첼
커험!
That's Chandler.
- 쟤는 챈들러
- 안녕하쇼
How do you do?
-What's?
-Well, he's....
- 저건...
- 그러니까...
He's doing some thinking.
사색 중이외다!
-What happened?
-You kissed my girlfriend!
- 어떻게 됐냐?
- 남의 여자랑 키스한 놈!
I like those sunglasses.
저 선글라스 근사하다
"Like them" like them? Or "I'd like
to get store credit" like them?
선글라스가 탐나는 거야,
상품권이 탐나는 거야?
바 파 나뽈리!
자, 칠면조 대령이오
This turkey is ready.
Where can I wash up?
- 손은 어디서 씻죠?
- 따라와요
Let me show you.
The towels are hanging next
to the sink.
타월은 세면대 옆에 있고
거기 있는 화장비누 써요
-And you can use the fancy soap.
-Thank you.
고마워요
Fancy soap? I thought we were
saving that for the pope.
화장비누?
교황님 드릴 거 아니었어?
See. He's nice, right?
근사하지 않아?
그렇긴 하다만 괜찮겠어?
자꾸 아버지랑 비교될 텐데
Do you want a relationship
where you can actually say:
"That's not how your dad
used to do it"?
Everything looks great.
Where should I sit?
정말 먹음직스럽네요
난 어디 앉죠?
Saved you a seat.
이쪽이에요
Sick, sick, sick, sick.
잘 꼬여 들어간다...
I'll get it.
내가 갈게
Got you!
속았지롱?
That doesn't sound
like thinking to me.
사색하는 태도가 불량해!
-Sorry!
-You shouldn't be talking at all.
- 미안
- 닥치고 있어
You've got too much thinking to do
to be talking and joking.
반성할 게 무지 많을 텐데
어디서 자꾸 까불어
Okay, you got it!
네, 알겠습니다
Ross, pass me the yams?
로스, 감자 좀 줄래?
그래, 조이한테 으깬 감자
있는데 교환하시든지
Joey's got the mashed potatoes
if you want to exchange them.
Will you stop!
What's the matter with you?
- 그만둬, 왜 자꾸 이래?
- 우리 손님 있다
We've got company.
Nothing's the matter with me.
왜 그러긴, 나도 인간인 이상
감정이 안 상할 수 없잖아?
I'm not completely devoid of sentiment.
I have feelings.
Okay, fine.
그래, 좋아
You can't tell, but I'm breaking
the tension by mooning you guys.
니들 분위기 한번 띄워보겠다고
나 엉덩이 깐 거 혹시 보이냐?
All right, look!
야!
If this is a big joke to you,
forget about it.
너한텐 이게 장난 같겠지만
내게는 중요한 일이야
This means something to me.
If it doesn't mean anything to you,
then get out of there.
별거 아니라고 생각되면
바보 되기 전에 빨랑 나와
Otherwise, you're just
an idiot in a box.
You're right. I'm sorry.
This means a lot to me.
미안하게 됐다, 우정을
되찾는 중차대한 순간에
I want to be friends again.
I swear I won't say another word.
오늘밤엔 입 닫고 있을게
-So you'll take this seriously?
-Absolutely!
- 진지하게 나갈 거지?
- 그러하옵니다
That sounds like another word to me.
또 입 열었다?
Are you going to take this seriously?
진지하게 반성한다고?
Okay!
좋았어
Don't say that I have no sentiment.
난 뭐 사람도 아닌 줄 알아?
This is a movie stub
from our first date.
우리 첫 데이트 때
영화 티켓
This eggshell is from the first time
you made me breakfast in bed.
네가 처음
아침 만들어준 계란껍질
This is from the museum,
the first time we...
이건 박물관에서
우리가 처음... 함께 했을 때
...were together.
Maybe I exchange gifts sometimes,
but I keep the things that matter.
선물은 가끔 교환하지만
의미 있는 건 소중히 간직해
I don't know what to say.
I'm sorry.
할말 없다, 미안해
Though you're not
supposed to take these.
근데...
이런 걸 들고 오면 곤란해
It's, like, a million years old.
백만 년 전 유물이라고
We actually have people
looking for that.
그거 찾느라 사람까지 풀었어
-Mind if I smoke?
-Care if I die?
- 담배 피워도 돼요?
- 빨리 죽으라고요?
No, I'm just kidding, I'm just kidding.
Go ahead, smoke.
농담이에요
괜찮으니까 피워요
This always happens.
- 이런, 맨날 이래
- 어디 봐요
Here, let me.
Thank you.
고마워요
You have very beautiful...
정말 아름다운...
외눈이네요
...eye.
My friends think this is weird.
친구들은 다 이상하대요
Even the one in the box?
궤짝 안에 있는 친구도?
It's not weird, is it?
이상하지 않죠?
I thought it would be. I almost
canceled, but it really isn't.
그래서 나도 오기 싫었지만
꼭 그런 건 아니잖아요
I know. Me and your dad,
that's totally separate.
맞아요, 아버지와는
완전히 끝났으니까
I totally agree.
그럼요
우린 서로에게 끌리는
사이인데... 그렇죠?
We're two people
who find each other...
...very attractive.
Right?
-What?
-Nothing, nothing.
- 왜요?
- 아니에요
No, really.
Was that not okay?
말해요, 마음에 안 들어요?
아뇨, 좋았어요
아찔한 키스였어요
No, that was good.
That was a good kiss.
-lt reminded you of
-Don't say it!
- 이런, 혹시 아버지하고...
- 거기까지만!
-lt did, didn't it?
-Yes!
- 사실이군요!
- 그래요!
돌겠군!
I know!
알아요
이런!
미안해요, 정말 미안해요
God, I am sorry. I am so sorry.
It's okay. It wouldn't be Thanksgiving
without a little emotional scarring.
괜찮아요, 추수감사절은
의례 서로 할퀴는 날이니까
You know what's even worse?
기분은 나쁘지만
친구들 얘기가 맞았어요
My friends were right.
You know what's worst for me is you remind
me of a younger version of my mom.
난 어머니하고 입 맞춘
기분이에요, 처녀였을 때
네
왔어?
그래
-I want you to know how sorry I am
-It's okay.
- 이번 일은 정말...
- 그 정도면 됐어
-Chandler's the one I'm mad at.
-Well, I'm still sorry.
챈들러한테 화난 거야
그래도 미안해
-ls he here?
-ln the box.
- 지금 있어?
- 궤짝에
- 챈들러?
- 지금은 말 못해요
He can't talk right now.
Why not? What's going on?
왜요? 무슨 일이죠?
He's trying to show Joey
how much he means to him.
조이와의 우정을
증명하는 거예요
-By being in a box?
-Joey had reasons.
궤짝에 들어가서?
다 사연이 있어요
They were threefold.
삼겹이래요
그렇군요...
You not being able to talk
might make this easier.
말을 못한다니
더 쉬울 수도 있겠네요
Listen....
저기...
잘 들어요, 난 둘도 없는
친구 사이를 깨고 싶지 않아요
I don't want to be someone
who comes between two best friends.
I can't stand seeing
what this is doing to you guys.
옆에서 지켜보기도
고통스럽구요
And I don't want to be
the cause of that.
내가 원인을 제공했잖아요
I don't think we can see
each other anymore.
우리 이제 만나지 말아요
I'm going to my mom's in Chicago.
당분간 엄마가 계신
시카고에 가 있으려구요
I'm going to stay there for a while.
I think this could have been
something really amazing.
잘될 수도 있었는데
But, you know, this is
probably for the best.
하지만 이게
최선인 것 같네요
You know?
이해하죠?
I'm going to miss you.
보고 싶을 거예요
Goodbye, Chandler.
안녕, 챈들러
Open the box!
궤짝 열자고!
What?
뭐?
지금이라도 붙잡아야지
자, 어서 나와
He can still catch her.
Get out of there! Get out of there!
- 그럼...
- 난 다 풀렸어, 나와
We're going to be fine.
Get out!
- 그래?
- 사색도 지나치면 해로워
You did some real good
thinking in there.
I mean, this is....
- 그러니까...
- 시끄러, 임마
You could still catch her!
가서 꽉 붙들어
네 산타가 주는
성탄절 선물이야
And merry Christmas
from your Secret Santa!
All right, who got Chandler?
Because I need to trade.
누가 챈들러 비밀 산타야?
나랑 바꾸자
He sees her!
- 만났다
- 붙잡았어
He's catching up to her.
She sees him!
마주보는데?
They're hugging!
껴안았다
He's taking her purse.
지갑을 빼앗잖아
That's not them.
쟤들이 아닌데?
신고해야겠다
I'll go call the police.
There they are!
저기다!
All right, get a room.
그래, 방 잡아라